《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
公民们
Citizens!
我给你们介绍新的副总统 盖尤斯保塔博士
I give you your new vice-president, Dr. Gaius Baltar.
你是我孩子的父亲 无论什么都改变不了这个事实
You're the father of my child and nothing is ever gonna change that.
我知道有个地方你可以躲起来 在那里你会很安全
I know a place where you can stay where you will be safe.
我还能活多久?
How much time do I have?
几周 一个月最多
Weeks. A month at the outside
除非癌细胞转移到你脑部如果那样的话你
Unless the cancer goes to your brain. If that happens...
我恐怕测试呈阳性
I'm afraid the tests are positive.
是恶性肿瘤
The mass is malignant.
在左胸扩散
It's advanced well beyond the left breast.
我恐怕测试呈阳性
DOCTOR: I'm afraid the tests are positive.
罗斯林女士
Ms. Roslin,
这个手术  当然 切除肿瘤
the surgery, of course, will remove the mass.
罗斯林部长?
STANS: Secretary Roslin?
怎么?
Yes?
我是教育联盟的内林斯坦斯
Naylin Stans, from the Education Alliance.
你说你想谈谈?
You said you wanted to talk.
是的
Yes.
对不起 斯坦斯先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Stans.
我要承认 我很惊讶收到你的消息
STANS: Have to admit I was surprised to get your message.
总统很惊讶我会发那些消息
ROSLIN: The President was surprised I sent it.
曾经我们的首席谈判代表被暴力对待
Once our chief negotiator got a billy-club to the head,
我们估计阿达的政府认为我们必定失败
we figured Adar's government had written us off as a lost cause.
我在做教育部长很久以前就是一个老师
I was a teacher long before I was Secretary of Education.
任何课程都是因为我们放弃才会失败
And causes are only lost when we give up.
总统女士?  能听到我说话吗?
Madam President, can you hear me?
我们尽量让她舒服一些
COTTLE: Let's make her as comfortable as we can.
哦  神啊
Oh, gods...
049小队  星芭儿  战斗机巡逻队准备离开
STARBUCK:Starbuck, zero four niner. CAP is away.
卡拉狄加 收到  049小队
Galactica, roger that. Zero four niner.
安全飞行
Safe flight.
安全并且迟到了他妈的20分钟
Safe and 20 frakking minutes late.
昨晚没睡好吗 星芭儿?
Did you have a rough night, Starbuck?
你飞太快了
STARBUCK:You're way out of line.
你只管跟着我  把火气留给吃你这套的人
Just follow my lead and save the attitude for someone who cares.
670号凯特  收到
KAT: Kat, six seven zero. Roger that.
请求允许试试机炮
Request permission to clear guns.
收到 凯特
STARBUCK: Roger that, Kat.
试一下你的机炮
Clear your throat.
它妈的! 武器故障!  武器故障!
Damn it! Weapons malfunction! Weapons malfunction!
卡拉狄加!
Galactica.
卡特 你还好吗?
Kat! Are you good?
我没事我没事
I'm good, I'm good.
刚才怎么了?
What the hell just happened?
你的翼炮炸了
STARBUCK: Your port gun's blown.
稳住  我们回去
Just keep it steady. We're heading home.
卡拉狄加 我是星芭儿  报告紧急情况
Galactica, this is Starbuck. I'm declaring an emergency.
我们有两架受伤战机  请求优先降落
We've got two bent birds, requesting priority clearance to land.
星芭儿 卡拉狄加 飞行甲板已经准备好了
LSO:Starbuck, Galactica. Flight deck is yours.
你不如索性在更衣室里打死我们呢 头?
Why don't you just shoot us in the locker room, Chief?
还可以减少点机体磨损
Save the wear and tear on the ships.
卡特的机炮没问题  我亲自检查的
Kat's guns are clean. I checked them myself.
是吗  但我不相信这只是凑巧
Yeah, well, I don't believe in accidents.
头 好像有点不对劲
Chief, something's not right.
重量减少了  太轻了
The weight's off. It's too light.
我还发现另外三个和这个一样 混在正常的中间
I found three more just like it, mixed in with the regular rounds.
弹壳被弄薄了
The casing's been weakened.
在炮膛里断开了 下一个炮弹打在上面 砰
It falls apart in the barrel, the next one hits it, bang!
她的机翼没整个断掉  算她运气
She's lucky she didn't lose her whole wing.
有个别正常 这么多 肯定有人破坏
One bad round's a fluke. More than one is sabotage.
都卸下来!
Pull them all!
你们都听到头说的了  都卸下来! 快!
CREWMAN: All right, you heard the Chief! Let's pull them all! Let's go!
总统怎么样了 医生?
ADAMA: How is the President doing, Doc?
她快死了 她自己也知道
She's dying, and she knows it.
我想给她打了一针吗啡来镇痛 但是她不原意
I offered her a shot of morpha to ease the pain, but she wouldn't hear of it.
结果呈阳性
The tests are positive.
他们是老师不是恐怖分子
ROSLIN: They're teachers not terrorists.
总统先生在我们派兵镇压之前
Mr. President, we should at least speak with the strikers
至少应该和罢工者谈一下
before sending in the troops.
他们是老师  不是恐怖分子
They're teachers not terrorists.
他们看上去和恶棍一样
They're acting like thugs.
他们上次游行把两个警察送进了医院
Their last demonstration put two policemen in the hospital.
还有六个人把自己绑在教育会堂前
Six of them have chained themselves outside the Hall of Education.
在我看来 他们是罪犯
As far as I'm concerned, they're criminals.
他们收入过低 他们的学校就要解散
Their pay is sub-standard, their schools are falling apart,
他们的罢工已经有几个月了  你也知道
and this strike action has been gaining momentum for months and you know that.
我不懂为什么我们不和他们谈谈呢
I don't understand why we're not at least talking to them.
做为总统最有意思的事之一
One of the most interesting things about being president
就是你不必向任何人解释什么
is that you don't have to explain yourself to anyone.
你已经约了斯坦斯见面  对吗?
You've already set a meeting with Stans, haven't you?
当然  只要你同意  总统先生
Obviously only if you approve, Mr. President.
她现在不适合做任何事
BALTAR: She's really in no good state to do anything,
更别说是国家大事
let alone to conduct any Government business.
别把我当死人
Don't talk about me as if I'm not here.
你们很快就会有足够的时间谈那些
There'll be plenty of time for that soon enough.
比利 你能…
Billy, could you...
当然
Of course.
先生们 我叫你们来讨论塞昂人
Gentlemen, I called you here to discuss the Cylon.
卡特尔医生
Dr. Cottle, would you...
能不能把你早上告诉我的再和他们说一遍?
Would you please tell them what you told me this morning?
我不是遗传学方面的专家 但是我能看懂验血结果
I'm no expert in genetics, but I can read a blood test.
那个塞昂人胎儿
That Cylon fetus
显示出一些特殊的遗传异常
is showing some very peculiar genetic abnormalities.
你的报告中从没有提到这些博士
I haven't seen any of this on your report, Doctor.
是没有 嗯 正如卡特尔医生所说
No, well, as Dr. Cottle says,
他不是这方面的专家 而我是
he's not an expert and I am.
我测试过几次但是我还没有得出结论
I've been through the tests and I wouldn't say that there was anything conclusive
我可没说过有什么结论 只是有点他妈的奇怪
I didn't say conclusive, just damned odd.
是的
Right.
总统女士
BALTAR: Madam President?
正如你所知  这个塞昂人莎伦
As you know, the Sharon Cylon
对舰队有非常重要的战术价值
is of considerable tactical value to the fleet and...
也许你和你的研究对象接触过密  博士
Perhaps you've gotten too close to your subject, Doctor.
这很困难 所以我要解决它
This is difficult, so I'm gonna cut right to it.
允许这东西生出来可能会导致恐慌
Allowing this thing to be born could have frightening consequences.
为了舰队安全
For the security of this fleet,
我相信塞昂人的怀孕必须被立即终止
I believe the Cylon pregnancy must be terminated
以免为时过晚
before it is too late.
总统女士 我想…
Madam President, I'd like...
我想你们所有人都会理解  上将
I thought you of all people would understand, Admiral.
总统女士
BALTAR: Madam President,
我不理解  这毫无意义
I don't understand. This makes no sense.
做为总统最有意思的事之一
One of the interesting things about being president
就是你不必向任何人解释什么
is you don't have to explain yourself to anyone.
谢谢你们  先生们  我  我有点累了
Thank you, gentlemen, I'm a little tired.
先生们?
Gentlemen?
不是我危言耸听 但是我有点担心
I don't want to seem alarmist, but I am perturbed.
我想总统的疾病正在影响她的判断力
I think that the President's illness is affecting her judgment.
特别是对塞昂人
Especially when it comes to the subject of...
我觉得她挺清醒
ADAMA: She seemed reasonably coherent to me.
那么我不得不告诉你这么做对科研的影响
Well, then I'll have to appeal to you on scientific grounds.
杀死这个孩子
Destroying this child
将会严重影响我对塞昂人的物种研究
would seriously impact my studies of the Cylon subspecies.
总统决定了  我也支持她
The President made the call. I'm backing her.
你看 恕我冒昧  总统决定的依据是…
With all due respect, the President made the call based on evidence
卡特尔医生提供的证据 而他…
presented by Dr. Cottle and he...
你最好振作起来
Pull yourself together.
你将会成为总统
You're about to become President of the Colonies.
你将不得不作一些非常困难的决定
You're gonna be asked to make some very hard decisions.
你应该表现出你能胜任这一职责
Act like you can handle it.
神啊
Gods.
你上哪儿去了?
Where have you been?
我上哪儿去了?
Where have I been?
我从未离开过你 盖尤斯
I never left you, Gaius.
哦 好的
All right, yeah.
是的 嗯 是的可以这么说
Yeah, metaphorically speaking.
那不过是一周以前 我 哦
It's just it was weeks ago and I...
我不在的时候你肯定非常痛苦
I'm sure you've suffered mightily in my absence.
你知道 嫉妒是一种非常丑恶的感情
You know, jealousy's a really ugly emotion.
为什么要…
What is this lingering controversy over my affair
吃你实体拷贝的醋呢
with your three dimensional duplicate?
我不是嫉妒  我是担心
I'm not jealous, I'm concerned.
哦  是吗  担心什么呢?
Oh, yeah? Concerned? About what?
我们的孩子!
Our child!
哦  现在你担心了?
You're concerned?
好吧  告诉你  总统正打算杀了它
Well, for your information, the President intends to kill it!
一旦罗斯林死了  你就是总统
Once Roslin's gone, you'll be President.
你可以用你新的权力去保护我们的孩子
You can use your new authority to save our child.
哦  好像真的一样  你没看到阿达玛怎么盯着我看的?
Yeah, yeah. That's good. Did you see the way Adama looked at me?
写在他脸上的那种轻视?
The contempt on his face?
我要做总统  是的
I will be the President, all right,
但是没有军队支持 我什么也干不了
but without military support I might as well be an anointed dogcatcher.
是的  你也有你自己的优势  如果你愿意使用的话
Yes, well, you have your own resources, if you'd use them.
怎么  你不知道我说什么?
What? You don't know what I mean?
是的  我不知道你在说些什么
No, I don't know what you mean.
那个核装置
The nuclear device.
那个阿达玛提供给你研究用的
The one Adama provided for your research.
还有一个办法
There is one way.
不到万不得已
NO. 6: I didn't wanna have to ask...
我不会提出这个要求
I didn't wanna have to ask you for this.
但我真正需要的…
NO. 6: But what I really need...
真正需要的
But what I really need to complete the project...
是一个核
Is a nuclear warhead. Is a nuclear
弹头
warhead.
你完全疯了
You're totally insane.
我正在帮你  你个白痴
I'm trying to help you, you idiot.
如果阿达玛坚持杀死我们的孩子
If Adama remains committed to the destruction of our child,
这是我们唯一的希望
it may be our only hope.
这很难开口
There's no easy way to say this.
关于这个塞昂人
It's about the Cylon.
总统已经决定她的怀孕将被终止
The President has decided that her pregnancy will be terminated.
什么?
What?
为什么?
Why?
在帮胎儿验血的时候
Doc Cottle discovered some anomalies
卡特尔医生发现了一些异常
in the fetal blood work.
那不是很正常吗?
Isn't that expected?
也许
Maybe.
但是总统觉得
But the President believes
允许这个胎儿完全成长
that to allow the baby to come to full term,
可能会对舰队形成威胁
it constitutes an unacceptable risk to the fleet.
我不懂
I don't understand.
自从莎伦从卡布里卡回来后一直在帮我们
Sharon's only helped us since she came back from Caprica.
她甚至还自首了
She even turned on her own.
来救她自己
To save her life.
不要混淆了求生欲望
Don't mistake the will to live
和真正的同情 中尉
for genuine compassion, Lieutenant.
她依然是敌人
She's still the enemy.
她知道吗?
Does she know?
还不知道
Not yet.
那该由我来告诉她
Then I should be the one to tell her.
就这些吗  长官
If that's all, sir.
希洛
Helo.
我不指望你能同意这个决定
I don't expect you to agree to the decision,
但是我需要你接受它
but I need you to accept it.
我们在谈论我的孩子  长官
We're talking about my child, sir.
我的一部分
Part of me.
但是我猜把它叫成塞昂人就比较容易下手杀它了
But I guess it's easier to kill when you call it a Cylon.
解散
Dismissed.
你的意思是有人在破坏我们的弹药生产
So you're saying someone's been tampering with our ammunition?
弹壳不会自动落下
Shells don't unload themselves.
我听说你命令
What's this I hear about you ordering
卡拉狄加和帕伽索斯的战斗机都停飞
both Galactica and Pegasus fighters to stand down?
这是你让我复职空军指挥官付出的代价  长官
The price you pay for reinstating me as CAG, sir.
也许那是个错误
Maybe that was a mistake.
也许我根本不在乎你怎么想  长官
Maybe I don't give a damn what you think, sir.
放松点  你们两个
Take it easy, both of you.
事实上  我们一直在两艘舰上互通消息
The fact is we've been sharing stores between the ships.
在弹药供应查清之前  没人会飞
And nobody flies combat until our ammo supplies check out.
如果塞昂人攻击  我们将无力防守
Leaving us defenseless if the Cylons decide to pick a fight.
我们之前就无力防守  只不过我们不知道而已
We were defenseless before this. We just didn't know about it.
李  找到是谁干的
ADAMA: Lee, find out who did this.
好了
APOLLO: All right.
对不起 我找阿夏雅尼克
Excuse me, I'm looking for Asha Janik.
阿夏 她就在那儿
Asha? She's there.
不要搞出很大动静
APOLLO: Let's do this quietly.
阿夏雅尼克?
APOLLO: Asha Janik?
阿达玛上尉
Captain Adama.
我要给你父亲带个信
I have a message for your father.
他们可以抓我!        抓住她!
They may take me... All right, stop her!
但是我们还有很多人
...but I'm one of many!
我们对卡拉狄加的死亡军队宣战!
We have declared war against Galactica's army of death!
走
MAN: Let's go.
塞昂人不是我们真正的敌人!
The Cylons aren't our true enemy,
是军队拒绝谈判!
it's the military that refuses to negotiate!
我们只要和平!
ASHA: All we want is peace!
要和平! 要和平!
Demand peace! Demand peace!
压抑过度 嗯?
So much for being discreet, huh?
我们在雅尼克的舱里发现这些小册子
ADAMA: We found these pamphlets in Janik's quarters.
像某种宣言
Some kind of a manifesto.
向塞昂人祈求和平?  这些到底是什么人?
"Demand peace" from the Cylons? Who the hell are these people?
塞昂人同情者
Cylon sympathizers.
只是没想到他们如此有组织
I just had no idea they were this organized.
我想知道她如何上了我的舰
I want to know how she got aboard my ship.
机库甲板人手不够
The hangar deck's short-staffed.
我们只能用一些平民来做地勤工作
We've been forced to import civilians to handle some of the grunt work.
很明显
Apparently she's...
她是个派亢人  在格林里夫从事维护工作
She's a Picon, worked maintenance on the Greenleaf,
无犯罪前科
no known criminal affiliations.
呵  不再是了
Until now.
现在听听这个:
Now listen to this,
别怕 我们不是恐怖分子 但阿达玛的战争机器
"Do not be afraid. We are not terrorists, but we will not sit back
迫使我们投入残酷而无意义的冲突时
"while Adama's war machine continues to press us
我们也不会坐以待毙
"into cruel and futile conflict. "
他妈的
Gods damn it.
她成功了
Well, her demonstration's worked.
消息已经传遍了舰队
The news is already spreading across the fleet.
我知道
I know.
有个自称代表那些破坏分子的人
We were contacted by a person claiming to speak for the subversives,
要求在卡拉狄加会面
demanding a meeting on the Galactica.
想的美
Well, they've got stones, I'll give them that.
我已经同意了
ADAMA: Well, I've agreed.
什么?
What?
我们不是谈判
We're not negotiating.
我只想知道我们究竟在对付谁
I just wanna know what we're up against.
考虑一下后果 看来你还不明白
STANS: Considering the stakes, you don't seem particularly engaged.
那正是我们想要得到的结果 斯坦斯先生
The stakes are what we decide to make them, Mr. Stans.
如果总统用军队强迫我们回去工作
If the President uses troops to enforce his back-to-work order,
有人会受伤
people will get hurt.
甚至死亡
Even die.
有些事值得为之献身
Some causes are worth dying for.
不是这个
Not this one.
是个恶性肿瘤
DOCTOR: The mass is malignant.
医生
Doctor...
上将
Admiral.
我是罗严亚希
I am Royan Jahee.
你招呼客人的方式很特别
You have a unique way of welcoming visitors to your ship.
客人 我呸
TIGH: Visitor my ass.
你这种人我们以叛国罪处死
We shoot people like you for treason.
上校 我只是想
Colonel, I'm only an interested party,
避免流更多的血
trying to prevent more bloodshed.
我对发生在你们毒蛇战机上的事很难过
I deplore what happened aboard your Vipers.
这艘船上有多少塞隆同情者?
How many sympathizers do we have aboard this fleet?
如果你想摧毁这个组织 你不要白费力气了
If you're trying to crush an organization, you can stop now.
这些人现在只是跟随着一个理念 而不是领袖
The people in this movement are following an idea, not a leader.
他们到底想要什么?
What the hell do they want?
和塞昂人和平相处
Peace with the Cylon.
你们想叫我们投降?
You want us to surrender.
他们先攻击我们
They attacked us.
只是在我们奴役了他们之后!
Only after we'd enslaved them!
你们自称军人  军事家
You call yourselves military men, strategists!
能不能告诉我凭现在的攻击方式和撤退
Explain to me how our current course of attack and retreat
怎么才能得到胜利?
leads to victory!
你可以装做无辜的旁观者
You can play innocent bystander,
但是我想你知道的不止这些
but I think you know more than you're telling us.
不管怎么说  你对舰队都是个威胁
Either way, you're a danger to this fleet.
上将  抓我是没用的
Admiral, arresting me isn't going to stop any of this.
也许是的  但这是个开始
Maybe not, but it's a start.
把他带走
Take him away.
好了  带上你们的橡皮手套
All right, get your rubber gloves on.
这些是那个雅尼克女人住处的所有东西
This is everything from the Janik woman's quarters.
上将认为在这堆垃圾中能找到些有用的东西
Somehow the Admiral thinks looking through this crap
也许会让我们对他们那个所谓的运动多些了解
is gonna tell us something new about their so-called movement.
那么..
So, um,
自从你上次“太空行走”后还没见过你几次
I haven't seen much of you since your spacewalk.
等等
APOLLO: Hold it.
这是什么?
What's this?
一个地勤要便携舰体地图干吗?
What's a deckhand need with a portable library reader?
Daru Mozu号
The Daru Mozu.
负责锑的提炼
A Tylium refinery.
那个雅尼克很熟悉爆破
And Janik's used to explosives.
我是空军指挥官 马上给我准备一个搜索队
This is the CAG. Get me a TAC team ready. Right now.
我不懂
BOOMER:I don't understand.
为什么他们要这么做?
Why are they doing this now?
我不知道
I don't know.
上将说他们发现在胎儿血液内有某些东西
The Admiral said they found something in the baby's blood.
不知为什么  罗斯林总统认为这对舰队是个威胁
Somehow President Roslin considers it a threat to the fleet.
不可能只为了这个
It can't just be that.
自从我来了以后一直在帮他们
I've done nothing but help them since I've come here.
我收起了我的愤怒
I've held back my anger.
我努力想告诉他们塞昂人并不都是一样的
I've tried to show them that Cylons are not all the same.
我们并非都是杀人犯
That we're not all murderers.
我认为他们内心深处依然怕你
Deep down, I think they're still afraid of you.
是啊
Yeah.
害怕
Afraid.
他们想知道什么是害怕吗?
They wanna be afraid of something?
是吗?  让他们来!
Yeah? Just let them come.
让他们来!
Let them!
让他们来带走我的孩子试试!
Let them just try to take my baby!
Let them try to take my baby.
莎伦  别这样!
Sharon, stop!
莎伦 别这样! 求你了!
Sharon, please, don't do this. Please!
听我说  听我说!
HELO: Listen to me. Listen to me.
听我说!
Listen to me.
莎伦 听我说
HELO: Sharon, look at me.
走吧    嗨 放松
GUARD: Let's go. Hey! Easy!
放松
Easy!
降落后 行动要快
When we land, move fast.
我们要找一个放置在Daru舰的空间跳跃引擎附近的爆炸装置
We're looking for explosive devices set near the Daru's FTL drive.
上尉 我好像在无线电里听到了些什么
Captain, I'm getting something on the wireless.
我想是从Daru Mozu舰上传来的
I think it's coming from the Daru Mozu.
我们都不想死但战争必须结束
WOMAN:None of us wants to die, but the fighting must end.
如果我的牺牲送给塞昂人一个信号并带来和平
If my sacrifice sends a signal to the Cylon that brings peace,
那这就是值得的
then it was worth it.
我这么干是我为我的孩子们和其他孩子们
I do this for my children and for the children that will follow them,
神的旨意
gods willing.
求和平 拉开 拉开!
Demand peace. Pull out!
求和平 拉开 拉开 拉开!
Demand peace. Pull out! Pull out!
拉开 拉开!
Pull out! Pull out!
有人死了
People are dead.
我为他们哀悼 上将
I grieve for them, Admiral.
我向你保证这次不过是小试牛刀
And I assure you the Tylium ship's just a taste of what's in store
除非有人愿意听我们的主张!
unless someone starts listening!
你听好了
You listen, and you listen well.
如有必要
I don't care if I have to interrogate
我会审讯这支舰队里的每个平民
every civilian onboard this fleet.
这种行为必须被制止
This is gonna stop.
你懂了吗?
Do you understand?
是的
Yes.
副总统先生 罗斯林总统坚持要你来
BILLY: Mr. Vice President, President Roslin insisted on your taking the tour.
她希望权力移交尽可能的顺利
She'd like the transition to go as smoothly as possible.
这些是什么?
BALTAR: What are these?
塞隆密探嫌犯 长官
Cylon agent suspects, sir.
那数字对她非常重要
That number means everything to her.
代表希望 那是我们的未来
It represents hope. It's our future.
是的 是的
Yes. Yes.
作为总统
Being the President is
的确职责繁多
a lot of responsibility.
离任总统给继任者…
It's tradition for outgoing Presidents
留封信是个传统
to leave a letter for their successor.
通常要在任期第一天打开
It's usually opened on the first day of the new term.
但总统几天内就会…
But the next few days are likely to prove
所以
hectic, so...
让我们祈祷她会好转
Well, let's just pray that she gets better.
好的
Let's.
抱歉
Excuse me.
是的
Yes.
副总统先生?
Mr. Vice President.
喂?
Hello?
是的
Yes.
我理解
I understand.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要见一个老朋友
I was told I might meet an old friend here.
很高兴看到你  盖尤斯
GINA: It's good to see you, Gaius.
你现在成了和平运动的成员了?
So you've become a member of the peace movement?
不管你怎么想
Well, despite what you may think,
我憎恨暴力
I've always abhorred violence.
能让我们单独待一会吗?
Would you excuse us, please?
他们知道你是什么吗?
Do they have any idea what you are?
当然不知道  即便是他们也接受不了一个赛隆人
Of course not. Even their dedication has limits.
我想你
I've missed you.
你看上去好极了
You look amazing.
我不能相信
I can't believe
你如此真实
how real you are.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
从我离开帕伽索斯
I haven't stopped thinking about you
我就一直在想你
since the second I left the Pegasus.
不要         我无法忘记你
No. I can't get you out of my head.
不要  现在不要        我忍不住
Don't do this now. Not yet. I can't help myself.
我不能  盖尤斯
I can't. Gaius.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不
No.
对不起  我只是还没有准备好
I'm sorry. I'm just... I'm not ready.
那么 有什么特别的原因让我过来呢?
So is there any reason in particular for inviting me around here?
因为你救过我
Because you saved me.
让我救你
Let me save you.
哦 又来了
Here we go again.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
你肯定感觉到了
You must sense it.
盖尤斯  舰队在崩溃
Gaius, the fleet's crumbling.
人们在互相攻击
People are turning on each other.
人们对军队感到不安
There are serious misgivings about the military.
当你成为总统
When you're President,
你可以利用你的权力使他们反对阿达玛
you can use the office to turn them against Adama,
为赛隆人来拯救我们铺平道路
paving the way for the Cylons to save us.
我喜欢和你在一起 但是…
I would love to be with you always, but...
我知道这很难  但这是唯一的办法
I know it's hard, but it's the only way.
不
No.
我不是你想的那样
I am not who you think I am,
我不会去毁灭人类
and I will not be responsible for the destruction of mankind.
如果早点发现  我们也许还有办法
If we would have caught it sooner, maybe we could have done more.
劳拉
ADAR: Laura.
我不喜欢今天早上我们处理事情的方法
I didn't like the way we left things this morning.
理查德  我知道
Richard... I know.
你已经认为那是个错误了
You've been thinking this is a mistake for a while now.
我刚见过斯坦斯
I just met with Stans.
教育联盟会让步
The Education Alliance is going to back off.
让步?
Back off?
劳拉  你许诺他们什么了?
Laura, what did you give them?
我向他们发誓
I made them a promise
我们会认真听取他们的不满  理查德
that we would seriously hear out their grievances, Richard.
我想你会很高兴他们回去工作
I thought you'd be happy they're going back to work.
劳拉
Laura,
你把我弄的很尴尬
you've put me in a very awkward position.
我没看出来
I don't see how.
大家都退一步
Both sides gave ground.
不只是你的老师们
It's not just about your teachers.
我担心下次的罢工
It's the next strike I'm worried about.
你刚告诉他们  只要他们把时间拖得够长
You just showed them that if they hold out long enough,
这个政府就会屈服
this administration will cave.
你希望我失败
You expected me to fail.
我希望你能守住底线
I expected you to hold the line.
不过这也不是什么世界末日
This doesn't have to be the end of the world.
你可以作为顾问而留下 我们依然需要你
You can stay on in an advisory capacity. Gods know we need your ideas.
你要求我辞职?
You're asking me to resign?
我没办法
I don't have any choice.
这已经不再是你我的事
This isn't about you and me anymore.
你说得对 不是
You're right, it's not.
几个小时以前你打算攻击这些人
You were willing to attack those people,
我还打算支持你
and up until a few hours ago, I was prepared to let you.
现在我要代表政府去参加卡拉狄加退役仪式
I am on my way to the Galactica to represent this administration.
等我回来 如果你依然想要我辞职  准备好战斗
When I return, if you still want my job, be prepared to fight.
通知上将
Notify the Admiral.
我是阿达玛上将
This is Admiral Adama.
正如你所知  罗斯林总统
As you know, President Roslin
会在卡拉狄加
has been aboard Galactica
度过最后几日
for the last few days.
她是个战士
She's a fighter.
但是现在  应该准备善后了
But as of this moment, her prognosis is grave.
我知道你们很多人相信祈祷
I know that many of you believe in the power of prayer.
如果那是你们的方法  我请求你们
If that is your way, then I urge you
为我们的总统祈祷
to pray for our President.
至于其他人  我希望你们和我一样
As for the others, I hope you will join me
把她留在我们记忆中
in keeping her in our thoughts.
上将  请别这么做
Admiral, please don't do this.
退下 所有人
Stand down, everyone.
让开
Give me room.
想想你在干什么  希洛
Think about what you're doing, Helo.
你是个战士
You're a soldier.
我是个父亲  和你一样
I'm a father, like you.
请别这样
Please, sir,
长官  给我一架猛禽  让我带她离开
give me a Raptor. Let me take her off the ship.
我会带她离开舰队
I'll get her away from the fleet.
我不能这么做  孩子
I can't do that, son.
上将 上将
BALTAR: Admiral! Admiral! Admiral!
博士 离开这里
Doctor, get the hell out of here!
我必须和你说  关于这个赛隆人孩子
I must talk to you concerning the Cylon child.
看来  我以前可能…
It seems I may have been
错了
wrong,
错的很厉害
very wrong,
当时我说卡特尔医生曲解了胎儿验血报告
when I said that Dr. Cottle misinterpreted the fetal blood work.
看  我又看了一下样品
BALTAR: You see, I had another look at those samples
发现一件很有意思的事
and I discovered something quite intriguing.
已知  赛隆人的血液完全无法和我们的区分开来
Understand, Cylon blood is virtually impossible to differentiate from our own.
过去是这么说  但是很明显一定有些不同
That being said, obviously it has to be slightly different
因为他们毕竟不是人类
because the Cylon is not human.
假如我们的血液
If our blood
看上去象这个
looks like this,
举个例子
for example,
而赛隆人的血液看上去是这样的
and the Cylon's blood looks like this,
也就可以假设混血儿带着两者混合体
then it's fair to assume that the Cylon-human is carrying an amalgam.
这是理论还是事实?
Is this a theory or fact?
赛隆人胎儿没有抗原
The Cylon's fetus contains no antigens,
没有血型
it has no blood type.
这就是为什么卡特尔医生说怪异
That's what Dr. Cottle was talking about when he said it was damned odd.
但是这不是怪异  只是令人吃惊
Except it's not damned odd, it's astonishing.
现在  我们已经知道
Now, knowing, as we do,
赛隆人比人类更耐久
that the Cylons are built slightly better to endure than their human counterparts
我想  会不会赛隆人的血液也被祝福了
I wondered, could the Cylon blood also be blessed,
允许我用祝福这个词
shall we say blessed,
能够抵抗疾病?
with a heightened resistance to disease?
所以
So
我把…
I applied a sample
莎伦胎儿的血液注入
of Sharon's fetal blood
从总统身上取得的癌细胞
to some cancer cells I took from the President.
我看到了什么?
What am I looking at?
什么也没有
Nothing.
这就是重点
That's the whole point.
癌细胞消失了  而且是在几个小时内
The cancer was gone and it was gone within a matter of hours.
你是说你发现了治疗总统癌症的办法?
Are you saying you've found a cure for the President's cancer?
还没试过
Well, it's untried.
很明显没试过  而且极端危险
It's obviously untried and therefore extremely dangerous.
不过
But, yes,
这很有可能
it's possible.
如果你打掉莎伦的孩子 你就永远不会知道
If you abort Sharon's fetus now, you'll never know.
现在你也许会感到刺痛
Now, you may feel a sharp pain.
莎伦  没关系  一切都会好的
Sharon, it's okay. It's gonna be all right.
我不喜欢你干的事
I don't like what you're doing.
我认为这不符合自然规律而且很危险
I think it's unnatural and damned dangerous.
是的
Yes, well,
根据病人目前的情况
given the patient's current condition,
我不认为还会有什么更差的结果
I am not sure that I see the downside.
也许她命该如此
Maybe it's just her time.
那么这次
Then for once
也许我能给大家带来希望
perhaps I am the beacon of hope around here.
没事了
It's all right.
一切都好了
Everything's gonna be okay.
我在你身边  莎伦
I'm right here with you, Sharon.
如果你想达成协议 你的人必须解散
If you wanna settle this, your people have to disengage.
不再有不合作  不再有暴力行为
No more civil disobedience, no more acts of violence.
我要学生都回学校
I want our students back in school.
好的
Done.
我很高兴你打电话给我 部长女士
I'm glad you called, Madam Secretary.
我也是
Me, too.
恐怕测试呈阳性 是恶性肿瘤
DOCTOR: I'm afraid the tests are positive. The mass is malignant.
发生什么了?
BILLY: What's happening?
她在抽筋  护士  给我10cc…
She's convulsing! Nurse, get me 10cc's of...
帮我给她侧身
COTTLE: Help me get her on her side.
护士  护士!
Nurse! Nurse!
不  别动
No, hold it.
不敢相信
I'll be damned.
总统女士?
BALTAR: Madam President?
波尔塔博士?
Dr. Baltar.
看到你太高兴了
It's so very good to see you.
不不  别动  别动
No, no, no. Don't. Don't move. Don't move.
总统女士
BILLY: Madam President.
她怎么样  医生?
How's she doing, Doctor?
我从未见过这种情况
I've never seen anything like it.
她恢复还要段时间
It'll be a while before she's 100%,
但扫描结果很明白
but the scans are clear.
癌细胞消失了
The cancer's gone.
你肯定?
Are you sure?
消失了
It's gone.
谢谢你
Thank you.
上将
Admiral.
你看上去好些了
You seem better.
好多了
Much.
你还关着那个…
Are you still holding the spokesman
新教派的发言人吗?
from the new faction in the brig?
是的
Yes.
带我去见他  好吗?
Would you take me to him, please?
当然    多谢
Certainly. Thank you.
我等你穿衣服
I'll wait for you to get dressed.
罗斯林总统
JAHEE: President Roslin.
亚西先生 对吗?
Mr. Jahee, isn't it?
我想我们该谈谈
I thought it was time we met.
请开下门?
Would you open the door, please?
照做
Do it.
我们会听取大家的想法
All these people want is to be heard.
你们中有人差点摧毁了锑的提炼设备
A member of your group nearly destroyed our Tylium refinery.
在我们对话之前
Before we can even begin to talk,
我要你个人保证  不会再发生类似攻击
I need your personal assurance that there will be no more attacks.
我告诉过上将  我没有直接联系…
As I told the Admiral, I've had no direct contact with anyone.
继续谈判需要信任
Genuine negotiations require trust.
不要对我撒谎
Do not lie to me.
我会和他们说
I'll talk to my people.
让他们明白
Make them understand.
好极了
Excellent.
我会洗耳恭听  也许你现在只是在敷衍
Then I'll listen, maybe even act.
但是如果你食言
But if you renege,
我将要求上将消灭你和你的人  决不容情
I'll insist the Admiral hunt you and your friends down without mercy.
你看上去很满足
NO. 6: You seem very content.
莎伦的孩子安全了
Sharon's child is safe.
阿达玛和罗斯林
Adama and Roslin have agreed that more study
同意在激烈措施
is required before any
被执行之前进行更多研究
drastic measures are taken.
但是因为救了罗斯林 你失去了
Yes, but by saving Roslin, you've denied yourself
成为合法领导的机会
your rightful place of leadership.
你真是让人猜不透 盖尤斯  我永远无法理解
There are many aspects of you, Gaius, I will never understand.
你不会的
You wouldn't.
我想你也同样猜不透你的肉体拷贝
And neither, would I suspect, your corporeal counterpart.
你爱她吗?
Do you love her?
这是什么?
What is that?
罗斯林给我的信
The note that Roslin wrote me.
本该在她死后打开
To be opened upon the event of her death.
"波尔塔总统我给你我真心的祝贺"
"President Baltar, I offer my sincere congratulations.
我知道我们有分歧
"I say that knowing we've had our differences
而我对你的入主也持有保留意见
"and that you take office despite my many reservations.
你也许是我见过最聪明的人
"You may be the most brilliant person I've ever met,
但你的才智被肉欲淹没
"but your intelligence is unleavened by compassion.
你必须使你的种族责任感
"You must be reminded of your ethical responsibilities
高于你那自私的需求
"and challenged to rise above your own selfish needs.
我写这封信并不是要伤害你  而是希望你能敞开心扉
"I don't write this to hurt you, but to beg you to open your heart.
要知道舰队的人们希望从你那里得到的不仅是领导
"Understand that the people in the fleet look to you
而且还有安慰
"not only for leadership but for solace.
和公正
"Justice.
想办法给他们所需要的
"Find a way to give them that,
你就会成为伟大的领袖
"and you will be a great leader.
劳拉罗斯林
"Laura Roslin. "
我为舰队做了那么多
BALTAR: And after all I've done for the fleet.
我为她做了那么多
And after all I've done for her.
罗斯林从来就不信任你
Roslin's never trusted you.
她在各方面不断对你产生坏的影响
She's undermined you at every turn, and now...
现在我们知道她永远不会信任我
So now we know she's never gonna trust me.
这不再是政治斗争  盖尤斯
This is not a political struggle anymore, Gaius.
这是生死之搏
This is quite literally life and death.
总统向我保证  只要没有暴力行动
The President assured me that as long as there are no further acts of violence,
她会把我们的意见
she's willing to bring our concerns
带给12法人团和阿达玛上将
to the Quorum and Admiral Adama.
她想拖时间
She's trying to buy time.
她决不会和赛隆人谈判
She'll never be open to negotiating with the Cylons.
我不同意
I disagree.
我想今天我们取得了实质性的进展
I think we made real progress today
副总统也是
and so does the Vice-President.
波尔塔?        是的
Baltar? Yes.
就在我离开前  他要求见我
Just before I left, he asked to meet with me.
他要我们耐心  他会在内部做罗斯林的工作
He encouraged patience while he works with Roslin from within,
他这个包里的东西是对他诚意的证明
and he offered the contents of this case as proof of his sincerity.
里面是什么?
What's in it?
我不知道
I don't know.
他说应该由你来打开
He said that you should be the one to open it.